Four years of toil, pain and sacrifice boil down to one almighty evening under the Parisian floodlights. Ireland in the green through the great Johnny Sexton kick off what could be a Rugby World Cup night for the ages.
And the first relieving kick made by Ali Price in for Ben White and asking Hugo Keenan to run from deep.
Key man in the Ireland side that has won 16 matches on the spin. A national record, two more victories and the equal the most ever.
I hope we refer to often as tier one teams in the international game. Ireland getting into their shape, Keenan again. That's a touch.
Sexton, this is Ringrow is running the arc. Ireland looking for possession, Ringrow slices Scotland open, Hanson, James Lowe for the corner.
63 seconds gone. Ireland stupefied the Scots with first base poison in the Parisian cauldron.
So many weapons in this Irish arsenal. That was Gary Ringrow who opened it up. Not looking like much was on here but Scotland just ran out of defenders.
Some indecision there as Ringrow squared upfield and then heaps of options going through the hands. Lowe getting crucial blow.
That would be a huge test for the mental side for this Scottish team. Beautifully executed by the Irish players. Hard running, good distribution.
Again, so many options available for every Irish player on the field. What a start.
James Lowe was a try scorer in Ireland's most recent win over Scotland in March. He suffered from debilitating juvenile arthritis as a teenager.
He may never have dreamed he would reach this pinnacle of rugby union.
Johnny Sexton, Ireland's ultimate points machine. He's missed just once from the tee in 15 attempts in this competition.
He's missed another but that is a rippling beginning from this Irish machine.
Well such is the respect and the understanding of both these great rivals. Absolute silence for that kick but this was far too easy.
Just running out of numbers. I said off the top. If Scotland had any chance they had to plant some seeds in the ground.
That kind of defending is not going to do it. The number one team in the world are off and running.
The round of Scotland must win by eight points tonight. Before we start thinking about bonus points and the like.
We haven't beaten Ireland by more than eight points in a competitive match since 2001. 22 years ago.
Coach Gregor Townsend started at fly half that day.
That's a fine take.
That left back right left very much loose. Taking back.
Put some puck into the sky. Kim Warn comes forward and that's a fine take.
In the six foot five inch full back nearly two meters tall.
Gilchrist. 33 year old war horse in the second row.
Whistled his hands on goal for the first time and introduces Sione Dupu Lothu.
Australian born with common and Scottish blood in his veins. Schumann.
He was caught high so Scotland have a free play here. Russell.
Passed by to Dempsey on the touch line. Hanson sends him.
Russell again picking his options. Finding Schumann.
Russell.
Richard the captain.
Picks that one on to Kinghorn.
Stepping inside to Jones.
Split them up towards the Irish 22.
Still have that penalty advantage as they go from touch line to touch line. Russell.
Lovely ball on to Zander Fegerson. Scotland searching for a quick response.
Ireland steal it.
And MacBerry will bring them back.
Much better play from the Scots. Really confident on the ball.
Russell.
Controlling the ship. A few concerns there.
But again the Irish they bent a little bit there but they didn't break as they look at the review. Guy Easterby the defence coach.
Becker-Townsend 74th test in charge of Scotland.
His face style was eight times in the coaching box.
He's been on the losing side on every occasion.
That was the high tackle there.
Back around.
Doris.
Right out of the gates.
Don't think they could quite believe their luck.
Rob recommended. Neither could the coach.
That's how you start the game. Incredible isn't it.
This is exactly the tactic that Ireland are looking for.
The majority of their tries will be coming from these punching phases.
Getting in to these Scottish defenders.
Scotland conversely love possession as well.
And like Russell will relish having ball in hand.
On me.
And that decision there a reflection of the circumstances.
They said they need a win and they need to win by a margin.
So taking the line out rather than possible kickable three points.
Yes five.
I need you two metres please.
I need you two metres.
You fancy George Turner can clearly hear the call from his forwards at this line out.
Such as the din inside Scuddy Falls.
Turner breaks away.
And Hugh Jones makes a beeline.
For Johnny Sexton.
Price.
Rory Darge the young open side.
Wrapped up by Bandiaki.
Ritchie on the blind.
Scotland must make the most of these.
Attacking opportunities.
Russell. Lips around to the left.
Here's Jones.
Fandamerva. Static but still.
Steps out of two tackles.
Hanson chops the giant down.
Ireland have the penalty.
Over the goal.
Listen.
Big tackle from Hanson.
Fandamerva came back in field there.
And I have no doubt that the playbook is very much for the Scots around.
To Bilotto and Hugh Jones running hard.
Not the legend that is Johnny Sexton.
He's hit it twice.
From Jones.
There is those so-called red zone opportunities when a team is attacking in the 22.
But the ruthlessness of their attack is measured.
By how many tries they score from those positions.
And Scotland have let one slip through their fingers.
Number.
Five guys.
There is the reaction from Andy Farrell.
He's overseen 41 matches as I have seen.
He's only lost seven.
83% win success rates.
The best.
In the professional era.
Josh Fandaflea finds Cale and Doris.
To the.
To the Lansdowne and Dublin.
But a little knock on the floor.
Will give Scotland another attacking foothold.
Yes.
Well they're going to have to go to the bench early here.
That's all.
I think it's going to be an H.I.S. assessment.
The independent doctors on the sideline have seen something.
And they're going to have a little look to make sure.
They're well for the center.
That's the black Kinghorn is OK.
Make sure there's a space before the set.
Looking home will shoot down the tunnel with Dr. Jones.
And he's going to be able to get the ball.
They don't want the hands of the Kinghorn.
Will truth down the tunnel with Dr. James Robson.
Very longstanding very respected.
It's not the doctor.
All this is on for him for the time being.
And this is the table as things stand a win for Ireland.
We'd send them top and we'd put a place in the quarterfinals.
Where they would face the all blacks.
Next weekend.
So that's because we're staying seconds.
And they would take on the whole nation.
Whatever the upshots.
Whatever the outcome.
monumental showdowns in these knockout fixtures.
Well has there ever been a worse reward for winning a big match like this than to get the Oblacks
at a World Cup quarterfinal stage?
Yeah, yeah, no, no, okay.
You heard the call.
Please don't stand up, okay?
Massive opportunity now for Scotland in this scrum. Ireland have only conceded three tries in the Rupert World Cup.
Each of them have been from first phase and two of them have been from scrum, so this is
an opportunity that Scotland will have to try and take to them.
These are two of the best defences anywhere in world rugby.
Two teams with the top defensive statistics in Europe's Six Nations Championship earlier this year.
Fields of Aachen Rhein reverberates around Stade de France.
Godhead.
Straight down onto your knee.
Okay.
You heard our referee there, Nick Berry, saying the Irish front row player went straight down onto his knee.
So another opportunity for Scotland. Yeah, they're gonna go for the corner.
Keep the pressure on.
That's right, head went down to his knee.
As you said, Jamie, last time in the red zone, nothing to show for it.
They want to change that.
I reckon you went early on the second call and then the tight head went to his knee.
Okay.
So a bit more control, okay?
Pierre Schumann leads the charge for Scotland. He's built like a whiskey barrel.
Chest that must be 64 inches.
Big steal from Ireland, but Gibson Park has to take it over the touchline.
And Scotland will gain a few meters here and a reprieve.
Well, just some good insight into the conversation that goes on with the referee and the players.
Rob, you picked up a little question there. It's quite revealing.
Yeah, really good. Both teams great with discipline.
Less than 10 penalties for both of them.
Reach is getting a bit of tension, but the conversation with the referee was about what can we do better?
The props know that scrim time is so important as line out is.
Ireland haven't been functioning well in their line out throughout this tournament.
So that's a welcome sight for Peter O'Mahony.
The Scots do have a very good defensive line up themselves.
So it'd definitely be an area that Ireland addressed before this game.
I was just going to say earlier as well on that set, don't anticipate it.
Just listen in again here. The referee is still talking to the Irish front row boys.
Thank you.
Jamie, you good?
Okay, guys, water off.
Water off, guys. We'll get going.
Jordan, just up in front please.
It was Peter O'Mahony who got Irish fingertips on that last Scottish throw ahead of Richie Gray.
Scotland can knock at the Irish door again here.
They go to the captain Richie at the tail.
And they set the drive.
Ireland not budging an inch so far. So Scotland must play.
There's two for all two. Russell playing out the back.
Olly Smith, Darcy Graham, darts in the inside but he's well chopped down by Keenan.
And Ireland piling off their feets.
I think Ireland happy to concede out wide. They were exposed momentarily.
They've got enough bodies over there.
Yeah, and that's why you didn't get penalised for offside.
Oh, did you get that finned? Okay, so the conversation is the line out went past the
15 metre line so it ceases to be a line out and both sets of backs can come up and play.
And Russell, perhaps with some frustration they didn't score on that place,
sticks it deep into the stands knowing it's time for his forwards to get to work.
Scotland nudging towards 60% possession and they're opening another minute.
This is their fourth line out inside the Irish 22. Richie again is the target.
Try to take on this Irish juggernaut.
He's not going to use it. I need to see it moving forward.
Okay, nine, get going now.
They're not shifting so Price releasing Tui Polotu who
touched the ball under a meaty bicep and carries.
Russell standing flats, well taken by Olly Smith.
Anson stands up to the physical challenge.
Price to darts, can't escape the clutches of Ian Henderson.
Turner running direct, straight into his opposite man Sheehan.
Russell, a lot of blue jerseys off to the right. Tui Polotu to Smith who
I just saw a glimmer of space opening up, lost his footing.
Depsey now, former Australian international.
Tye Burn comes through and sacks Price.
Price bounces clear and gets it onto Darcy Graham.
Ireland detonating to that breakdown.
Harry stay back, it's a blue ball.
Stay there please, keep your leg down.
Scotland have gone 10 metres backwards.
Russell has to get it away quickly to Depsey.
Smith stepping.
It's Hugh Jones in fact, the dancing footwork.
Darge, Xander Fegerson.
Tackle release.
What a Chennai-ish lie.
Thank you, well done.
One of only four players in this team to have beaten Ireland.
Gilchrist juggles.
Just about holds on.
Eleven phases now for Scotland.
Stay down, stay down.
Ireland withstanding the onslaught.
Russell pulls it back for Hugh Jones.
Again cutting on the inside, again shackled.
All these green demons.
Even Pierre Schumann with all his bulk can't get any go forward.
Russell.
Trying to nick between two tackles.
Sheehan with a big one.
Darge.
Enough of the footwork from the open side.
Fifteen phases now for the Scots.
If Ireland can hold them out it would be a huge psychological boost.
Russell again for Schumann.
All squads clear.
It's all a bit chaotic now as Russell moves it for Dui Purotu.
From the Melbourne riding side saddle but Hakee deals with the Scottish centre.
Gilchrist back to Fegerson.
Very, very loose there, it's very unstructured.
And it's not on by Scotland.
He lost the ball.
He didn't play the ball.
It's illegal can't work and you've missed the ball on.
Eighteen phases.
Scotland pummel away.
Ireland smash the door in their faces.
Well the Irish fans let you know what they think about that.
The Scottish team have forced Ireland to make three times as many tackles as the Scots.
So great possession for Scotland but they're not able to break it down.
Russell wrapped up there.
Some big double tackles going in as well.
There the balls pop loose.
And as you said it got a little bit loose there.
And Rob that's got to be very encouraging.
retirement needs to be in the Irish defence system.
Absolutely.
We talked about how much possession Scotland like to play with.
That's why it's getting celebrated.
They did not budge past their 22.
Finn Russell is not a fly out that likes going for drop goals.
But in those situations you do wonder if he slips into the pocket and builds a score.
It would be a very interesting proposition.
Scotland looking encouraging with the ball at hand but that is a win for Ireland's attack.
Just look at the defence.
Sorry look at these numbers.
Massive amount of tackles from them in that phases.
You know and Scotland have to manage the game as well.
We said it's not going to be one or lost in the first 20-30 minutes here.
That kind of work they're forcing the Irish to do may pay off down the road.
So they won't be overly concerned but they would like to see some incursion into that green wall.
The British team has pride themselves on the attacking innovation and incision of his Scottish team.
So far they have no answer to the tsunami of green that is swamping and engulfing them with each passing carry.
Tom's on.
Crowds!
Five!
Six!
Penalty Ireland at Scrumpton.
I think it's their time here.
I need you to keep your feet up underneath you.
This time Scottish tight head.
He needs to bring his feet up.
Deemed to have gone down not taking his own weight.
So not only that defensive stand but now the relief and territory that will be gained.
Through Johnny Sexton's right boot he takes his time.
And this set piece to set piece with big defensive effort in play is right up.
Ireland's there you go on the near side the slip down.
Nick Perry in no doubt.
The perplexed look that adorns every front row who's ever been penalized in the history of Rugby Union.
But large across Xander Fegerson's mug.
North Ireland he can attack.
Omani rules the skies.
Sexton for Bundy Aki.
Sexton on the run around.
Matt Hanson's off his wing here.
He needs to pause habit. That's where the opening try came from.
Gillian pulls it back for Bundy Aki.
Two Mastercard Player of the Match awards in three games.
Dan Sheehan with his first start of this Rugby World Cup after a ligament issue.
Big shot from the Scots and that forces the knock on from Ty Burne.
This is off the top line-up ball meaning they don't catch it they release it quickly
and look at all those options again for the Irish.
This time Scotland get enough bodies across.
Just the air ultimately as they're trying to offload in tight quarters.
So that'll be a little bit of a boost to the men in blue.
Grant Gilchrist dislodging the ball from the grasp of Ty Burne.
The big lock.
The man who's captained Scotland on many occasions including against Romania last weekend.
He's also afraid of mice incidentally.
An unfortunate trait for a 6.8 inch bloke.
Anyone suggested that mice might be afraid of him?
Steady!
Nine up.
Dempsey breaks for Ali Price.
He changes direction and Oli Smith's left boot.
Can't go straight to touch Oli Smith and he hasn't.
Keenan, twinkle toes, floating with that white paint.
Just managed to avoid grazing the chalk.
Russell.
End of it in the Landward style.
Taken cleanly by James Low who can kick the ball a country mile.
And he has laced that to within a metre of the Scottish 22.
That's a bopper.
It's a massive kick.
This one does he put a foot in touch here as he slides over?
Whoa!
The fans of the stadium have just seen that view.
Up where the feed is.
Got it to back of the stand.
I think the referee's going to have a look.
The duggars seen it.
He's checked it and he's not clearly in touch.
I told the boys of that grown-in, the television match official, he said he's not clearly in touch.
Yeah, time off.
Just give me a second, okay, with the time off.
Not the end of it, sorry, I'm speaking to my timekeeper.
My TMO's checked that, okay, he's not clearly out.
So we're going to play the line out here.
Loads of big calls to see, he's not clearly out there.
I'll tell you when time's off, okay?
I don't want to keep talking to you.
Are we outside here?
Guys, we're outside.
Gregor Townsend is flabbergasted.
Hugo Keenan did appear to stuttle over the white line.
The official's happy, there's no clear evidence that he was in touch.
So Scotland attack on set, with 80m out.
George Turner has to break off on his own.
Tagburn, very good in those positions.
And Tagburn has pilfered it back through Ireland.
And now the green machine can crank into gear again with Bundy Aki.
More carries, more meters made than any player in this competition heading into round four.
Fadifler.
Getson Park, 6th in assessing his options.
Lovely pass, O'Malley's galloping away.
Gets it to Hanson.
And Hanson can't get it.
Hanson can't hold on with the line beckoning.
Well, the fairytale ending might have been written there on his 100th cap.
O'Malley was into space.
Just spilled that final pass.
Good footwork, nice angle of run, stepping inside the defender.
That left arm frees up the ball.
But Hanson can't hold on.
He's a big moment and despite that shot,
that shocking start in the first minute by the Scots,
you've got to give them credit,
they've hung on in absolute anguish for the Irish
as they look to put in their second try.
A real point of difference so far in this first 20 minutes
is how Ireland really don't accept that tackle.
They're running through the contacts,
they're keeping that ball alive which creates a quick ball.
It seems Ireland are doubling up on their tackles
and it's proving very efficient in how they're defending.
Rob, talk to us about accepting the tackles.
What does that phrase mean to a rugby league person watching at home?
It's known as the Ardis-Sarvaius statistic.
How far you can run beyond that first point of contact.
That extra two, three metres really has absorbed more players in the defensive line and creates more space.
Jamie Ritchie is walking wounded right now.
He missed Scotland's win over Romania up with a head injury.
He's now nursing what appears to be a rather sore midriff.
And Matt Fegerson is on in his stead.
And we may not see the Scotland captain again this evening.
Well not in the first 18 minutes he wanted to see.
Side down.
Such a great competitor.
80 appearances for Edinburgh rugby.
Great that he was cleared.
All precautions taken about a head injury.
That last one was really good.
Alright Sam again, ok?
Alright, let's find out. Time's on.
Well the word is, Jamie Ritchie's done.
And Finn Russell is the new Scotland captain.
So much rest in his
unflustered, unflappable shoulders.
Look at those action areas.
46% of this.
19 minutes played inside the Irish 22.
But contrast that stat with the one in the top left corner of your screen.
5 points to nil.
Jack Dempsey looks to make some meters for the Scots.
Another press can affect the clearance now.
And she has keenened back.
And that's nicely done by Scotland.
Great energy from the Scots.
Dempsey doing what he needs to do from the back of the scrum.
And the wee man in the 9 jersey putting his left boot to it.
Absolute despair from the skipper.
Sometimes a picture doesn't take any words.
For some of these players, Jamie Ritchie included.
This will be the biggest game of their lives.
And it's so cruel that the Scotland captain
invalidated out with Weston Porter gone.
Clean ball for Ireland.
Johnny Sexton introduces Aki and Doris.
To punch some holes in the first line of Scottish defence.
Gibson Park.
And that cancels.
And Mark Hanson.
Tap back by Ireland.
So if under three can play.
Cale and Doris.
Much back in the tackle.
Gibson Park.
He saw that Olly Smith was out of position.
And Graeme.
He's got his back quickly enough.
Calls for the mark.
It appeared to be in his 22 when he caught that ball.
Which is why the Irish crowd on that far side
are voicing their disapproval.
And just to let you know
what's happened there.
Because he's in his 22 meter.
And I think he probably was.
Just puts out the bad arm and he's allowed to mark the ball.
A fair catch if you will.
Now he's been able to clear.
I think that ball was in touch.
There won't be a knock on there.
Yeah, yeah, send him off then.
A little bit closer than I thought there.
Maybe he was jumping back in.
He's quite substantial.
Matt Hanson the latest.
To require some medical attention.
And on comes Stuart McCloskey.
Who although in unfortunate circumstances
will savour his opportunity.
To compete at this stage.
Have been kicked out of this Ireland back line by.
Just this year fully by.
Talik and Andy Farrell and Joe Schmidt before him have had.
With Ringrose and Aki and Robbie Henshaw.
Who's injured tonight and not playing.
And they've been able to get a little bit of a break.
A chance for McCloskey to make his mark.
And I think that is a big feature.
And Andy Farrell's team there is so much depth.
But quality depth.
Real depth players that can perform at this level.
That will rise to the occasion.
And won't let the side down.
And you need that when you're the number one team in the world.
And you're trying to go further than the Nair's team's ever gone before.
In a Rugby World Cup.
And the crowd is just uncontested.
News now!
Again, Gibson Park tests.
The strippers back three of the year.
Darcy Graham can't take it.
And Ireland can choose.
Squam or line out here.
Well I see it.
Green jerseys there.
Trying to get to Darcy Graham's head.
This unfortunate.
Doesn't quite time it right.
They're going to choose the line out of the Irish.
It's both full tries.
That's good. Okay, Graham come on in please.
Darcy Graham up to five in the Rugby World Cup.
Only being outstripped by Damjan Puno.
And put Italy to the sword.
And Lyon last night for France.
Ireland are on the attack again.
Mikloski's first touch.
Into Bundy Aki.
Big meeting of muscle.
In the middle. Finn Russell with the good shots.
Sheehan.
He really is the prototype for the modern hooker.
Six foot three.
110 kilos. Butts turned over.
And Russell can push Ireland back deep.
He looks for the 50-22.
Keenan saves the day.
It's great coming from Hugo Keenan.
He ran half way across Paris to get there.
But that's a big moment for the Scots and for Gregor Townsend.
Well what could have been.
Had that kick rolled into touch of course.
With the 50-22.
Law kicking from one side.
They've still got possession a bit further out.
See if they can build something here.
They took meters please number two.
They're not messing around at line out time.
But Ireland steal a second.
And the set piece of walls.
The ghosts of so many matches in this fixture.
Coming back to Hog George Turner.
And the Scottish line out.
Okay use it now please Lyon.
Gibson Park.
Huffs it.
William again catches that one cleanly.
And a significant due rest.
Price has to squirt around some heavy carriers at the base.
Thuy Pallottu looking up a bit for Scotland here.
Thuy Pallottu straightened and took the contact.
Russell again probing the corners.
That one easily dealt with by Jameson Gibson Park.
James Low is down injured on half way.
So Ireland attacking with 14.
Now defending.
Russell sizing up his options.
This is a bit of space in behind Gary Ringrose.
Cute footballing work from Gary Ringrose.
Not bad with ball in hand either.
And Ali Price being harried by Ringrose.
Lashes it out.
And it's a good yardage game for the Irish.
And can he play from Gary Ringrose?
Well there I say with a gala coming in there.
Managing the football.
The odd shape of the net.
And the ball.
The odd shaped football in Rugby World Cup's case.
Watch the touch of the left foot.
Just traps the ball.
He knows what he's doing there.
Absolute class and then he gets the bounce.
Come back and play at the Parc des Princes for Paris Saint-Germain with skills like that.
Time's up guys. Time's up.
James Low's eyes being split.
Just gets a finger from his own team mate.
Looks like maybe some friendly fire there.
But Rob the atmosphere here is still remarkable.
And you've got to say after that start Scotland will be happy to still be only 1-1.
The contests are all over the park.
This is a great one building.
James Low and Darcy Gray.
But the kicking battle for me is what's exceptional.
Finn Russell nailing spirals into the corner.
Low just nursing the eye from a stray finger.
Okay guys we're going to get going eh.
Battles everywhere.
And you've got to feel for Blair Keighon who will not be taking part.
Failed as HIA.
Absolutely devastating on the sideline.
The ball.
And the ball.
You can see the tears swelling in Blair Keighon's eyes.
It's his 50th cap.
But player welfare is paramount.
Any suspicion of concussion.
Any symptom of concussion.
And the player plays no further part in the match.
Just to fill you in.
That's a process.
They've gone in with an independent doctor.
They've set questions.
They have standards they need to meet.
So there's no guessing in this.
And again it's all about player welfare.
And Richie as well will be joining him.
And Scott is trying to get back into this match.
That could be crucial as well.
Scotland only have two backs on the bench.
Now they've got one.
Oli Smith is already on.
As Ireland weave their attacking tapestry.
And Aki frees the hands.
Here's an opportunity.
It's Hugo Keighon.
Ireland cleaves Scotland to ribbons.
Hugo Keighon sears over the corner.
And Scotland to the mountain.
A familiar proportions to scale now.
First phase attacking brilliance from the number one team in the world.
Ball out the back.
Short ball.
But the hands are free so that keeps it alive.
And again the off load.
Keighon gets the try.
But what execution from the Irish back line.
Perfection.
And the Irish back line.
Hugo Keighon in the program.
Always the best put back.
He wasn't picked up by the Leicester province.
They didn't offer him a contract.
He hired his own sprint coach.
He worked like a beast on the field.
And in the paddocks at home.
And now he is a world cup try scorer again.
World Cup try-scorer again.
Sexton from wide on the left once more.
This one sails down the middle.
And in a game Scotland had to win by 8 points.
They trail 12-0.
Great win and watch Sexton, he's going to get the ball back again.
He handles twice.
The team scores. Aki doing his job.
Probably the most impactful player in this whole World Cup.
And Keenan, the former seventh player, gets the reward in the far corner.
Ireland have a firm grip on this match.
And an even firmer one on top spots in Rugby World Cup Pool B.
Which would set up a mouth-watering quarter-final against the All Blacks.
Ollie Smith.
Scotland have time but they have fired so few meaningful shots at this Irish defence as yet.
Will that go forwards?
That's come off a green hand.
No it didn't say the referees.
It's about nothing clear.
Xander Fegerson.
Flung onto by Ty Gurn.
Pitching great.
He's in the water.
His father Tuifohe will be watching back in Melbourne with his little brother Davi.
Pride Rugby family, the Tuikolotus.
His little brother Mosece with the Warrataj in Australia.
Russell inside too, Farnham-Ervyn.
And Ireland hold him up.
Farnham-Ervyn manages to free a big arm and hit Russell.
Jones, what a tackle by Ndiaki.
Jones clears it away in the nick of time.
Schumann, a lot of men outside him.
Schumann takes the more industrial approach.
Russell, Gail Crist dips his enormous shoulders into Cailan Doris.
Again, Scotland building phases and pressure but once more this fabulous Ireland defence.
Holding firm.
Russell, side ball, Jones again marauding.
Ireland over the ball.
Ireland win the penalty.
Look at Andrew Porter.
Another one side on the ball.
120 kilo, Boulder, wedging himself over that ball.
Karathriss, how do you move this man?
Well, fantastic tackle and look what it means to him.
This is what team defence is all about, doing your job and when the opportunity presents,
as it did there because the Scottish player was isolated,
you do your work, you win the penalty and the team advances down the field
through the right boot of your captain.
Ireland winning every battle that matters.
Jamie, we talked about it Rob, interesting to see if you picked up any vibes down there.
But the problem with being down two scores is that Scotland now have to actually start to chase the game.
They get out of their own game plan.
They know they need at least a score in this half.
And Ireland are supremely good at maintaining the lead.
They don't often give it up.
That's their stronghold, that's what they look to do.
It just looks as though they're playing with a different level of intensity,
both with and without the ball at the moment.
Once more, Puker O'Mahony, the Centurion, claims the ball.
And sheen, oh, it's lifted up by George Turner.
Bit of hooker on hooker, tete-a-tete.
And now three.
Fours just here, four just here.
Just open up if you can, thank you, just keep your arm there.
Gibson Park, the motion addicted out from everything,
mighty fame of Xander Faberson.
Ireland change direction, Gibson Park for Stuart McCloskey,
who takes some stopping, he's a huge man.
Gibson Park, the one-two is Sexton.
A little Irish sprite, the pace setter.
Moves Ireland deeper and deeper into the Scottish 22.
Third try for Ireland, could be terminal for the Scots, even at this stage in proceedings.
Gibson Park away, Kygburn,
the Munsterman caught on the five-metre line.
Gibson Park, Cailan Doris, they've got an overlap down the left.
Shuman holds up Doris, then has to let him go.
Ireland so close to an all-important third score.
Irish fruit wedged on Scottish throats.
Gibson Park, dummies of darts.
Cotch's shorts. Ireland's at the penalty advantage.
Ireland can smell Scottish blood, and they're in again.
This is Emerald supremacy.
And it's Ian Henderson, who batters through
this faltering, failing Scottish defence.
And they're almost out of sight.
Well, the man with two World Cups under his belt gets the try in the end,
but to a man, every green jersey is firing into rocks, recognising the need.
Look, the scrimmage gets isolated, and the boys are piling in,
making sure they can win that rock, unselfish play.
Then it comes to Henderson.
Just real intensity being applied at all the right moments by the Irish.
Ireland score 22 points against Scotland in March.
They're almost up to that tally.
It's seven and a half minutes of this first 40 left.
Sexton slots the extras, and Ireland can practically chase the quarter-finals.
Well, for me, it's when Gibson Park has a go at the line, the boys get there.
Henderson wisely ducks under the Scottish tackle and reaches out.
And so much to cheer about for these fans in the first 30 minutes here.
Brilliant shots coming in from our many, many talented camera operators around the ground,
capturing the emotion, the contrast.
Irish arms in the air, Scottish backsides glued to the seats.
Sexton, camera away.
Finn Russell wants to play.
Scotland already need a miracle.
Oliver Smith, stepping through the middle.
Bryce, which is really on the side to Pierre Schumann.
Call him the sheriff of the Scottish camp.
He's in charge of dishing out the punishments and the fines,
but Leightoness seems to be wearing the wrong kit.
Tackle down!
Matt Faberson running down a blind alley, tries to find a chink of light,
but all Scotland are facing is green.
Chris, releasing through Kaloutu, steps and then can't find Hugh Jones,
but cries of obstruction from Ireland, not feeded by Nick Berry.
Richie Gray, the Glasgow lighthouse.
Neck roll, blue seven, neck roll, blue seven.
Scotland will have a penalty here because Loli Darge with illegal clearance.
There's a neck roll by blue seven, and a previous rock.
That was the voice of Brett Cronin, the Australian television match official
who came in not only to your broadcast here, but also to referee Nick Berry.
Letting you know there was a neck roll, which is a clean out technique
that's no longer allowed to the Scots in trying to secure possession
of the neck roll.
Just roll here and see if we got it from our cue.
Yeah, there it is, you can't pull from the shoulder.
I think it's Andrew Porter again being the pest in there, getting rolled out.
He's had a big first half.
Well, that answers our question.
How do you shift Andrew Porter?
You have to do it illegally sometimes.
It's a good spot by Brett Cronin, our television match official.
He does perform that roll.
He'll feed in little bits of insight and information to Nick Berry.
The officials on the pitch are running the touchline, haven't seen.
What will Gregor Townsend be thinking?
He's got to somehow rouse his troops at half time.
Into some kind of revival.
Things could yet get worse.
They're going forward, they still miss side more.
And slowly, deliberately.
Painfully marching Scotland backwards and backwards again.
They've got a penalty advantage as well.
Dan Sheehan breaks off, hits Gibson Park.
This is relentless Irish attack.
Van der Vleer, Porter.
On the line, on the line.
They hold them up a metre out, but Ireland come again.
Ireland always come again.
Come around there, it's the same old.
George Turner's mall infringements.
No, he's come around.
We'll give him another shot.
It's the same mall, so he's got to join from behind those folks.
That's what I saw, I can't, I'm not going to have an argument about it.
Five penalties now considered by the Scots.
Yeah, I didn't see it like that.
So difference of opinion there, Finn Russell acting as the captain.
The lone voice to be able to have a discussion with Nick Berry.
The Hubbard, the Irish team.
They're not getting attached, so keep your eyes open.
Irish pack, throw down the gauntlet.
Dan Sheehan, tucks and trundles.
Porter, change of direction.
And poor old Nick Berry has run the most convincing of W lines.
Oh, Nick, you've ruined it, mate.
Come on, a former professional strongman.
You've got to anticipate that pass, Mr Berry.
Well, that's how good the deception was.
Five of them on the move, and Berry's the only one who could stop them.
That is pretty much a try.
Well, the irony of this from a Scottish point of view is that Nick Berry has made the most telling try-saving intervention.
Wow, they were looking good there.
But Jamie, how about the diversity of threats this team holds?
They've done it through driving line-out, they're off a set-piece move.
The backs have carved open an open play and off set-piece.
This has been fairly comprehensive with two and a half minutes to go.
They've pretty much done it in every way possible.
And the sway of the green.
Scotland and Fringe again.
Second strong penalty conceded by Scotland.
Walking round blue.
Sixth penalty in total.
Yeah, and they deemed that they were walking around.
Scotland can't pull that scrum around to the side.
See as the scrum sits here, great shot from the cable cam.
As they walk it around and pulled it around, said the referee.
Now Gibson Park tries to keep it alive, playing advantage.
They're going again.
Ireland assemble their monsters for another mighty raid on the Scottish line.
Porter feeds it out.
Short on the line.
Ireland inches away from a bonus point try.
By advantage, blue offside.
Scotland offside, Ireland have the penalty should they need it.
Sexton flings it wide, Kieran's away, can he catch him?
Now they catch.
Ireland a see right towards the knockout rounds.
This is a first half annihilation by the men in green.
Wow, they hit away at the line.
They ship it wide.
Sexton a little bit of hesitation, but great take from Kieran.
Maybe some question whether he got it down.
Sexton realize he was unmarked.
Good finish here, getting his body low.
Does he get the ball down? He bounces once.
Going to be interesting, I wonder if the television artificial may have a second look there.
Looks like Kieran just slid over and got the ball to the line.
Ireland with the bonus point try.
That means Scotland too.
Tries to take the bonus points.
That seems very very fateful right now.
Game clock has got 39.40 to go.
It's 39.40 gone.
2016, he wipes the sweat from his brown.
Takes all of his 60 seconds.
He's kicked it before the clock is up.
And rattles it between the posts.
Ireland 26.
Scotland 0.
And this is what the current score means for Rugby World Cup Pool B.
Ireland at the moment recording a bonus point victory.
They move from 14 points to 19.
From second place to first.
And set up a quarter final against the All Blacks.
In South Africa in second, facing France.
It almost feels like the job is done for Ireland.
Well the Springboks analysis team have got an extra 40 minutes I think.
To work on preparing for their quarter final.
This was billed as a clash for the ages.
Right now, it's one way traffic.
Just a remarkable step out of the gates in behind him.
Tim Russell with the short and restarts.
Picks the second half underway.
And Mission Improbable for Scotland.
Looks very much like Mission Impossible.
Hugh Jones.
Tries to score over West Island back in March.
Pierre Schumann.
Ireland heading for a ninth win in a row over Scotland.
They've played 30 times since the turn of the millennium.
Ireland have won 24 of those matches.
Richard Gray.
One of only four Scots in the team.
To have tasted victory against Ireland.
The last time that happened was 2017.
Under Vern Cotters, Aegis as head coach.
Bryce.
Matt Fagerson takes the way from Big Brother Xander.
Who came on early in the first half for Jamie Ritchie.
The captain's stricken and invalidated out of this match.
Dempsey.
Hardly been seen as Scotland's primary ball carrier.
Xander Fagerson again.
Scotland saw plenty of possession in the first half.
A lot of it in this middle third.
Were unable to escape the clutches.
The tendrils of this far reaching,
long lasting Irish defence.
Darcy Graham.
Even he can't unshackle himself.
Eleven phases now for the Scots.
Russell sees a gap.
Flings it away to Gilchrist.
And there's Johnny Dupouloutou.
Jack Dempsey again.
Onto Duran Fandemerba.
Just the second touch of the game.
In the forty second minute.
The Reds have kept him as quiet as a mouse.
Russell.
Lashed the crossfield away to Darcy Graham.
He took it well but he was in touch.
And even the innovation, the trick plays.
Are not coming off for Scotland.
Johnny Sexton fuming that he was tripped up off the ball.
And the tempers you suspect will fray in the Scottish team.
They've been given a battering of the rugby.
Peter Schumann might win the wrestling match.
Two proud nations you'd expect them to stand out for themselves.
Actually when Texans one of the players.
Nick Berry has referred it up to the team.
He says we're going to have to check this.
It's just a referee.
Wayne Barnes is right in there amongst it.
Well Johnny Sexton felt he was tripped off the ball.
After Darcy Graham was caught in touch.
Oh it's kicking off again.
It's like chucking out time in the Bastille region.
There's really not much here but in this cauldron that we've created here.
This incredible atmosphere.
Every push, every stumble.
And when that man Omani is involved.
He's trying to get the players to break up here.
Why not if you're Scotland?
Why not?
Change the dynamic.
Mix it up.
You've got to do something.
Peter Omani never takes a backwards step.
And he's not about to start in this one under the test match.
That's what starts all this way.
Just take him back and pull everyone down.
And it's now 23 blue.
Okay Greg, we'll just give him a chance to pull down mate.
So it's the trip from Ollie Smith.
Do you want to show us what that was?
Yeah sure.
So the first thing that happens is 23 blue puts his leg out and trips green 10.
Green 10 has a retaliation to him with a push.
And 3 blue comes in and flares everything up.
So that is what's happened.
I'll call it a day.
And it's been a fantastic game.
It's been a fantastic game.
So that is what's happened.
I can show you a replay of it now.
We're going to have a look.
Ollie Smith has come on as a sub.
It's deemed to have tripped.
The Irish captain Johnny Sexton.
And then it all sort of kicks off from there.
Okay your first camera angle is going to come now Nick.
So it's after Dyson Green kicks the ball in.
There's Ollie Smith.
The yellow card in football.
So that's the first action.
That's number 23 blue that puts his foot out for 10 green.
Yep.
And the second player in there from Scotland is number 3 blue.
It's not number 3 blue.
That's Sandra Fegerson who's very slowly making his move.
Number 3 blue is the first guy that comes in.
But there are plenty of blue jerseys.
And then I've reviewed everything else after that and there's nothing else to look at.
Yeah.
This is the initial action that started it Nick.
Yeah mate.
It's taken exception to the trip.
Yeah that's fine.
Johnny.
Okay you're going to come back on screen now Nick.
Yeah thanks mate.
So what started it all is he's taken exception to the trip.
Okay.
So that's what started the whole thing.
I didn't need what everything else happened afterwards.
Okay all the push and shove.
So 23 blue is going to go to the bend.
He was the one who started it for the trip.
Okay but talk to the guys.
We don't want everyone coming in.
Okay we've still got 35 minutes of foot in play.
Thanks.
Alright so 23 blues going to the bend.
Wow.
Things go from bad to worse for the Scots.
Ollysmith's act of petulance.
Punished with a yellow card.
He's off to the naughty step.
I don't know if I can agree with that.
It's obviously not something you want to see in the game.
It's a penalty definitely.
How this is a yellow card I don't know.
Yeah.
Alright I'll try mine.
This is when it got a bit more tasty.
A bit more WWF over there Rob.
Right in front of you.
It was right in front of me.
Triple H and the Rock wasn't it?
It was my earthquake and typhoon with those guys.
It was my earthquake and typhoon with those two.
Well that's the first yellow card Scotland have had in this World Cup.
That discipline's been great.
Can you please stay with your front?
You've been crowding a little bit.
Just stay with your front.
Seven penalties now conceded by the Scots.
And a yellow card to boot.
And Ireland will lap this up.
They look to continue their dominance.
That sheen.
Nick Berry almost getting in the way of the rampaging hooker.
Morrie inside.
Tag burn.
Bundy Aki blasting into the 22.
Ireland attacking the 14 men of Scotland.
Sexton sliding away from Turner's tackle.
Tackle now open up.
Cornemarie who's on at Scrum Half.
Into Ian Henderson.
Tackle release.
No no no.
Morrie.
Funnily Johnny Sexton.
Keen in the line hunting the hat trick.
Right they go.
Here's Trouble.
This is Gibson Park.
Darcy Graham cuts down the Scrum Half masquerading as a winger.
Scrain foot.
Morrie.
Gary Rynrose.
Sexton standing deep.
Ireland menacing again.
Gibson Park injecting the pace.
Sheen's on the wing.
Sheen's in for the try.
There is no let up.
There's no respite.
There is no mercy from Ireland.
Ben Jinn gets the try.
The hooker held the whip.
Watch the work wave from Jameson Gibson Park.
This is a classic in timing.
The lines angles are excellent.
This one goes wide.
Gibson Park steps infield keeps the play alive.
Does well.
Lots of support out there.
Then he pops up.
And watch as nine moves into the space.
He's moving now.
He keeps going.
And then the final pass is his to give to his hooker who stretched the Scottish defence.
We only have 14 on the park.
Try's all clear.
How important Gareth was the speed of ball that Ireland generated there.
They thrive off that quick rock recycling.
We've got this incredible stat that the Irish despite their dominance have only got four offloads.
And that's because they're passing before they engage the tackler.
So their timing and their lines of run are just literally very, very, very good.
And it's unstoppable right now.
Thank you.
Sexton pulls this one just wide to the left.
31-0 Ireland leads.
The Scottish defence looking fractured because it's all about speed of ball.
You mentioned it, but 70% of the speed for Ireland is less than three seconds.
That goes up to 78% in the opposition's 22 flat this tournament.
And that man curates most of it.
Ireland have decided they can do without Johnny Sexton for the last 35 minutes.
The captain, the totem withdrawn.
Jack Crowley, the young man from Munster on in his stead.
What an ovation the great man has received.
His job is done for the evening.
So too, virtually, as Ireland's.
What a luxury for head coach Andy Farrell to take his 38-year-old talisman off the park and put him in cotton wool.
The bubble wrapping Sexton on the bench.
She has bigger challenges ahead of him in this Rugby World Cup.
A date with the All Blacks in the quarterfinals next weekend looms for Ireland.
No, he's missed it.
He's got to have scored 19 tries in this Rugby World Cup, but with trialus against South Africa.
Scoreless thus far in close to 50 minutes against the Irish juggernaut.
Scott Cummings who's just come on for Grant Gilchrist in the second row carries.
Schumann, Russell.
Russell, there's Richie Gray.
Six foot ten inches over two meters tall.
Stay there.
Russell, Sionekepulotu facing Mpakee introducing Darcy Graham.
Price, Schumann again, carries into heavy traffic.
Faster ball for Scotland.
Russell, here's Hugh Jones running the arc.
Richie Gray with him.
Jones, good handling but when it's knocked down by Doan Fundimereva who couldn't hold on.
And Tye Ferlong is lulloping out of a desperate Scottish challenge.
Stay there.
It's like a falling buffalo, but Tye Ferlong.
Then it's from the knock on over.
Crowley has an age to pick his spot.
On the bounce outfoxes Finn Russell.
Russell, that languid relaxed style.
With a deception to Darcy Graham who can't get away from Doris.
Price, Russell, only two men outside him.
Hugh Jones is one of them.
Bundy Aki has watched that every time.
He stood up to that classic Jones.
Step and break on the outside.
Schumann, Scotland's most prolific carrier.
That's his tenth of the game.
And then Price interfered with it at the base.
Yeah, Schumann's doing his work.
Almost 50 meters made for the prop.
That's the one bright note for Gregor Townsend.
And they do have a penalty here.
Ireland are planning to bring on a battalion of five substitutions up front.
As Russell goes for a broke and Keenan keeps it in.
That is Scotland's knight in Michael Cosum.
Keenan goes to touch.
And now Andy Farrell will unleash his own Irish bomb squad.
Look at the talent and the beef in shot.
Our camera lens is barely wide enough.
James Ryan, Grand Slam European champion is on in the second row.
Ronan Kelliher is on at hooker.
Finlay Bealham and Dave Kilcoyne come on in the props.
And British and Irish lion Jack Conan wearing number 20.
Makes this first rugby world cup appearance of the competition.
And what an ovation Peter O'Mahony is getting.
There are a few men who have given so much for the Irish cause.
Who have nursed every grudge and strained every sinew.
And the Centurion troops off with another opposition back row.
Well and truly sickened.
Scottish line-outs malfunctioned.
George Turner of all people is back there.
Well that was pretty nifty.
Sliding and skating and then smashing.
No, no, no, it's still under.
Russell James Ryan hunts him down but the captain moves it away quickly.
It's really about pride at this point for Scotland.
They're beaten 27-3 by Ireland in the Rugby World Cup in Japan four years ago.
That was the first match of the pool and left them.
Heeding to beat Japan, they couldn't do that.
They crashed out at the pool stage.
And they are well and truly blowing their way out of this competition as well.
Russell has not been able to unpick this magnificent Irish defence yet.
But he has come up with a 50-22 and that will mean a Scottish throw in at the line-out.
Well not very many bright spots but that is pure class.
Because he's in his own half he just hammers it hard and low.
It takes the bounce.
A little bit of territory for Scotland but I don't think if I've seen Rob a greater sort of picture of job done as the legion of green jerseys, the impact players storm onto the field.
Some hurting Scottish bodies out there.
This is a problem for Scotland because they went 6-2 forwards and backs on the bench.
Ollie Smith on early for Blair Kinghorn meaning only Scrum Half George Horn is left.
So Horn is going to have to come on and play on the wing for the second Darcy Graham.
Four tries against Romania and he's scarcely had a sniff tonight.
George Horn, the seventh specialist he's on, is a makeshift winner.
Back in his hour, Price must play the full 80 at Scrum Half 2.
To the pull-out two, back for Russell.
Hammond watching in closely from the nerve.
Again, clattered.
Richard Gray running shots, running alone.
Russell, not vigorous in this time.
That's a goal!
Dempsey, one out carries for Scotland.
Finally making a little headway.
Cummings, dummies and then falls into the tackles.
Russell again, threatening this time.
Q Jones, again, can't get beyond Bundy Aki.
He's over that ball.
Out, keep your feet back.
It's a big pause on it.
Zander Fagerson, neatly onto Pierre Schumann.
Dempsey, Russell taking on the defence.
Russell dummies, can't do it all on his own.
No, no, 21, there's been a run.
Paul O'Murray's ordered off it.
Price, dummy in, Ireland hold him out.
This is as close as Scotland have come.
It's taken them the guts of an hour.
Penalty advantage Scotland, Matt Fagerson carries around the corner.
Scotland continue to keep it tight.
Amused are forwards.
We'll try for Schumann this time.
Irish players offside.
But credit this Scottish outfit, down to 14 men.
They're pounding away at the line.
That's all they can do at this stage.
Elizabeth's sin bidding period is over.
They won't be able to come back on until there's a definitive break in play.
Scotland tap and run.
Elizabeth reintroduced.
They're back to 15.
And Ireland have castled them, ransacked them, forced them off on.
Listen to this place.
Well, the players congratulate and this educated Irish rugby crowd too.
They know what this means.
There's any sort of technical eye had passed over this.
This Scottish attack is just a little bit too deep.
Often Russell, they're not really separating the Irish defenders.
Something to look at, but haven't really been able to break it down at all.
As the big man goes off and he's put in a fine chef.
11 carries 63 meters made ball in hand by Piers Schumann.
And a losing cause, but individual effort, nonetheless.
Rory Sutherland.
We finished last season in Northern Ireland with Ulster.
Comes on for him.
There is Princess Anne.
She will be impressed by the Irish display.
If a little disheartened by what Scotland have served up.
Princess Royal, the patron of Scottish rugby.
Doesn't that picture tell the tale?
Four years apart, two World Cups apart.
Scotland being torn apart.
By the repressible Ireland.
I was once captain at Canadian side at Murrayfield.
And the sleet started to happen as Princess Royal was supposed to beat all the players.
And she wisely showed a great touch and said, let's get on with this.
Let's get on with the rugby.
Not a day that we want to celebrate.
Scotland still yet to cross the whitewash.
Make sure he's got a spot to go into please.
Make sure he's got a spot to go down into.
Spray that solder up.
That's good.
Look at Andrew Porter.
Portrait of a warrior.
And like all good athletes he knows where the camera is.
And Jamie, we're now getting to a stage where this is a statement performance.
They're now sending messages to the other teams left in the quarterfinals.
About where Ireland are at the moment.
Set.
Time off.
Of course we've seen that from the All Blacks and we've seen that from the French this weekend.
A great weekend for rugby.
But for this Irish team in what is an incredibly fierce contest.
We thought it was going to be.
They have just dismantled the Scots.
Still 27 minutes to break in this match.
Cross.
And those eight successive Ireland victories over Scotland.
The average score is Ireland 25, Scotland 11.
It's looking a lot prettier for Ireland.
A lot uglier for Scotland right now.
Use that.
Plenty of time left on the clock.
There's Jack Crowley.
The quarter-backed monster for the United Rugby Championship title players.
Scotland go fast.
Ollie Smith back in the thick of things after a sin been in.
Cross.
Jack Dempsey escapes past the challenge of Lennon Keller and Fimli Bielum.
And so runs it into Richie Gray.
This will be his last appearance at the World Cup.
And he's been turned over. Ireland steal it back.
That's the narrative for so many of the men out there.
They may not get back here again.
Players on both teams know that this could be their last shot at the Rugby World Cup.
For Ireland there's still a long way to go potentially.
For Scotland it's all ending in tears.
Play advantage for a take off from Blue 4.
Tackle off the ball from Richie Gray.
On the 10-bit line midfield.
Right corner of the TMO.
Coming in.
On the 10-meter line, yes.
Blue 4.
That's correct, number 4.
Richie Gray is not going to go down without a fight.
Maybe some frustration coming in there.
And Rob the wave starts to swing around here and it's largely a green wave as we look at this incredible stadium.
I don't know who it was to be honest.
I just got a call from the TMO.
The atmosphere really building.
Blue on 7 green.
Scotland now looking at another replacement.
I didn't have my name on the card.
It's been atritional for them.
Finn Russell tried to create something but this is very much a difficult task on every single facet of this game at the moment.
We're just going to go quiet here and let you take in this atmosphere with television sets at home.
It's special.
Oh yeah.
It's a bit of a surprise.
It's special.
The bars of Paris and Saint-Geneviève will be doing a roaring trade tonight you fancy.
Thank you.
Ireland's line is a picture of perfection.
And they still on the third of the Scottish throws too.
They look to keep the scoreboard ticking.
Once again Murray.
Ringrose throws the dummy.
Kelleher.
Such competition for places in this Irish team.
Ronan Kelleher, Finlay Bealham vying with Sheehan and Furlong.
James Ryan too.
Captain Ireland.
Captain Leinster.
Crowley pulling it back for Bundy Aki who is sitting down as scuttling opponents.
Jack Devsie.
Rocked by Big Bad Bundy.
Murray goes blind.
Crowley.
I am Venice.
We are penalty in Venice.
Scotland in fringe again. Ireland can rampage again.
Crowley.
Stabs the kick over the top.
That's a peach.
Artistry.
Sheer magnificent artistry.
Ireland masters of innovation.
And so wonderfully kill a kill.
Gary Ringrose the try scorer.
Jack Crowley's gilded fingerprints.
All over this.
This doesn't happen without the go forward from those forwards.
The 23 year old puts the outside of his right boot to that.
Perfectly weighted.
Great finish as well.
And Ringrose who started this match.
Look at the youngster. He knows it looks good.
He's hoping. And yes it is.
Ringrose in for five.
Gary Ringrose in amongst the tries again.
Jack Crowley.
Ireland have a worthy successor to Johnny Sexton.
Another off the Academy production line.
It's a great big party at Gary Ringrose's parents house in Dublin.
When Ireland won the Six Nations Grand Slam.
Just over seven months ago.
I reckon the Ringrose household will be a buzz just now.
As Crowley lines up the conversion.
Off the post.
No luck for Jack Crowley.
But Ireland's move on to 36 unanswered points.
Lee Dewey is going to take a shot here.
Just taps it with the outside of his right foot.
The weight and the distance was perfect.
And the second half.
The first half.
The second half.
The third half.
The fourth half.
That physically sums up the frustration.
The Scottish team.
A terrific take in the air.
Ireland seizing upon it.
And Ireland are far from done yet.
Ringrose.
Footed wide to Gibson Park.
He's got the legs whirring again.
Pocket battleship duel with George Horn.
Tackle now, his knees on the ground.
Crowley.
Keenan into a thunder flea or world play of the year.
Tackle open up 20.
In 2022.
Ireland.
Leaving those patterns.
Tackle open up.
And those beautiful attacking pictures.
Crowley, another little kick this time.
That one harder for Ringrose to get after.
Scotland win it back.
Nolly Smith throws it way beyond to Poulotu.
Doan Fandemaver has to try and bake a kick with crumbs.
But they can tackle the monstrous winger.
And that's the way they've kicked Doan Fandemaver out of this match.
Russell.
Saw space.
Looking for the penalty, doesn't get it.
And Ireland on the counter with Hugo Keenan.
He drills it back through the arms of Olly Smith.
He's been bamboozled by the ball and he's knocked it on at the second time of asking.
And that is...
A summation of Scotland's nights.
And look at Bundy Aki.
He sounds the battle cry.
Russell tries to get the call here.
The referee is right on top.
It says Nolly ran straight into him.
And then again, just summing up what's been going on for Scotland.
The bounce not going their way.
Let's go guys.
Look at Aki.
He's been outstanding all tournament today.
He's got all the go forward for Ireland.
And Rob, such an impressive player on both sides of the ball.
Defense and attack.
Yeah, if you're picking up four players, they'll be well cooked.
Bundy Aki is really good.
And attack.
Yeah, if you're picking up four players, they'll be well cooked.
Bundy Aki is right at the top of that list.
Everything he does is just power driven, goes forward, gets the game line and then creates opportunities for those around him.
It's worth noting as well, Ireland's record victory over Scotland.
It's by a margin of 30 points.
That came in a Six Nations drubbing in 2015 when Ireland were going for the title,
clinched it on the final day at Murrayfield in Edinburgh.
Without stripping that margin just now.
I wonder if those two senior heads there that we just saw in shot know that stat.
Fine!
What a gift the Irish team have given Peter Omani.
Six!
He's hung his cap.
Seven!
Little solace to Scrum Pantley going against Ireland.
Russell again gambling.
Tripling that ball towards the corner, but Ruinrose watches it all the way.
Keeps it in.
V.P. Mel leading the chase for Scotland.
The 37-year-old prop who's just come off the bench.
Russell might as well chance his arm at this stage.
Hope foxes Ruinrose.
Flings the medical ball away and it's well scooped up by Jack Dempsey.
Bryce to Gray.
Dupu Lottu looping around.
Cummings, there's the dummy.
Ewan Ashman goes in to help.
Scotland desperate to avoid the ignominy of being nailed.
All the pre-match talk from the Scots was talk of belief.
Gregor Townsend said we believe, said this is our moment.
This is Ewan Ashman's moment.
Scotland are on the boards.
63 brutal, mortifying, trialous, pointless minutes.
Scotland at last have troubled the scoreboard.
Ewan Ashman gets their opening try.
Yeah, you sense the Scottish weren't going to leave this stadium without something to show for it.
And Finn Russell gets the initial break.
Nice pick up there.
And some finally, some go forward from the Scots.
Shifting out to the second half.
And some go forward from the Scots.
Shifting out to the side.
Nice hands from the centre there.
Dupu Lottu does well and puts away the replacement hooker.
23 year old Ewan Ashman.
Ewan Ashman born in Toronto, Canada.
His father was working, his father a proud Scot.
He plays in North of England, but very much a Scotsman.
And Finn Russell steers that one between the posts.
36 points to seven.
And those fans have something to shout about at long last.
Yeah, they perhaps knew they weren't favourites, but they thought they were going to be in it for a bit longer, I feel.
Scotland have used their eighth and final replacement.
Jodie Darge is off.
Luke Crosby, tough customer from a town of Livingston.
And Central Scotland is on, wearing jersey 21.
The full complement of Scottish replacement is on.
And if this match does play many more injured victims, Scotland will go down to 14.
Russell. Scotland look to move it from inside there in 22.
George Horn thrives an open play rate.
And suddenly it's opened up for Hugh Jones away from Aki.
The inside ball knocked back by an Irish hand.
And steering away is Olly Smith.
He's got support. Scotland are in again.
It may be a forlorn hope right now, but that is one of the tries of the tournament.
Finished by Ali Price.
And you wonder where this Scotland has been for the past 65 minutes.
Well finally some return for the Scottish outfit for going wide.
Tries all clear.
Tries been cleared by the TMO. A little regroup for the Irish team.
It's not what they expected. Russell adds two more.
But from deep in their own end they back themselves.
They've been commenting on the up and down to break down the Irish.
This time they go around the outside. Great pace exhibited.
By the Scottish backs. Hugh Jones stepping out of the tackle.
Unselfish play here. The show and go.
And Ali Price, the man who's been the talk of the town all week, gets a nice try.
This is the kind of rugby Scotland have longed to play.
This is when they're at their best.
Taking opportunities, manipulating defences.
But it looks like much too little, far too late.
As Ali Price gets his second in as many matches.
Matt Fegerson takes care of his restart.
Scotland this time shaped to kick.
Cannon off an Irish paw.
Zubokinen has it back.
Crowley.
Ian Henderson.
It's one of the violence third try.
Third of six they muster tonight.
Ronan Kelleher.
Caught by Vipianel.
Scott Cummings loop for that turnover.
Couldn't get it.
Ian Henderson off on the rampage once more.
Murray.
Jack Conan. Big moment for him.
Suffered a nasty foot injury that kept him out of the early matches.
Scotland with the penalty.
There is a momentum shift inside Stade de France.
And Russell again wastes no time.
The ball is in the net.
Stade de France.
And Russell again wastes no time.
And on this occasion does make touch.
The referee is going to kill that momentum for the moment.
As he wants to see.
James Ryan looked at his injured behind the play.
Yeah big shout going out for Scotland as they got hands on that rock ball.
There's the big carry.
From Conan.
And he's driven back and look immediately over the ball supporting his own weight.
Great technique.
From Luke Crosby.
James Ryan was panning an injury into this match.
That's one of the reasons Andy Farrell selected Ian Henderson ahead of him.
He had big concern to lose him.
Such an important player.
Such an ever present member of this squad.
And there you see.
All eight replacements on for the Scots.
Luke Crosby rearing Jersey 21 with the all important penalty.
And they look to salvage a crumb of solace.
In the final dozen minutes.
Well I think it's fitting for the Scottish health and they have at least this moment here.
Two tries on the board.
The stadium is pumping a bit here.
We're in a very difficult pool with the world number one team and the current world champions in South Africa.
It's always going to be tough.
They didn't have the first half they wanted.
The first phase of the defense is really let them down.
But at least now a chance to show the world.
How good they are and how they can play.
Well that goes to the front.
And to Glasgow's Scott Cummings.
Okay stop once.
Yes.
To the first receiver.
Dummy the past the Russell then.
Thunder for.
Richie Gray still full of running.
He knows this could be his last World Cup match.
Because it's been a rock.
You know Ditto for him at 37 years old.
Sutherland Russell delayed the pass.
And pulled it back behind Sonny to pull out to.
Who can't take it cleanly.
While screwing out of an Irish tour.
All right.
So there's no knock on the tackle.
Okay cool.
Chat with the referees.
Russell seems to think he's seen it.
I didn't see anything.
Disappointment for the man who started this match as captain.
Robbie sent a bit of buzz here.
Scottish side showing their pride.
They're going to get a bit of a clow into the midway through.
The fourth quarter here.
Very much a case of looking for that unstructured play.
That's what Scotland wanted all the way through this game.
Unfortunately it took 63 minutes to really see that.
That is the suppression that Ireland can really get on games.
Scotland move it softly away from the line out.
To equal or two again.
Trying to blast.
Chasm in the Irish midfield unsuccessfully.
Nell back to Russell.
And finally George Horn who.
The smallest man in the World Cup.
And the hardest to shackle as well.
And Ashman pops it up.
Drops it cold and Ireland can punish the Scots here.
Pump and tunnel from Beelan.
Jack Conan can maraud over halfway.
Dragged down by Sutherland.
Dave Kilcoyne.
That goal!
34 years of age.
The crossfield bomb.
On Dohan Fandemerva's side.
He leaves it for Olliv Smith.
He is caught.
And support though.
Fandemerva.
Wrapped up.
He's not been able to get those giant thighs free.
And stampeding at any point today.
Charge from Jack Dempsey.
Russell.
Cummins.
Sutherland.
Oh what a hemsen puck.
Wow.
About half a ton in body weight.
Sits the big prop down.
Russell now.
Hugh Jones.
Introducing Olliv Smith.
Fandemerva.
The left handed pass to Vipionel.
Into the final ten minutes.
Russell wide and flat.
Sutherland again.
He's created a bit of space for himself.
And from Proud Town of Hoyk in the Scottish Borders.
More Scotland internationals than any other town.
As you will see then we'll call the mark.
And take the sting out of this attack.
A smart play from Keenan.
They don't need to rush this.
They've got this game in control.
Side air plays, yep.
They've got their quarter final plays booked.
I can step on can't I?
Yeah you can.
The emotional intensity of playing against a team you know this well.
Knowing how much is on the line.
Knowing your World Cup can end in the evening.
Really does have a toll on the players.
Russell moves it quickly away to.
Fandemerva.
Who in turn asks Olliv Smith.
To make the first cut.
First man who's fine.
And will steal it back.
And it's Irish ball.
It's Bundy Akey's ball.
As it has been on so many occasions.
At this Rugby World Cup.
Jemison Gibson Park out of shot is hugging the left touch line.
He wants the cross kick.
Here it comes from Keenan.
Ryan.
Crowley now.
There is that delicate little boot.
This one folded by Finn Russell.
Conor Murray wraps him up.
Russell somehow frees up an arm.
Octopus style.
To two, pull or two.
Still going on.
Finn Russell has got.
Conor Murray pinned for three counts.
Here's Russell again.
Standing captain.
Ashman.
Smothered over the first Scottish try.
Bryce.
Sutherland.
The atmosphere inside Stade de France is quiet as it's been all evening.
Irish supporters content but subdued the Scotland attack.
The Spanish fans just hoping for a little more cheer before the final whistle.
Russell calls the mark.
Russell searching for a 50-22.
Finding only Jemison Gibson Park.
That would almost wound up in the Parisian flight path.
It was so high.
Price has found a lot of unguarded space.
Looking for the 50-22.
The ball's going to hold up on the five metre line.
Crowley tracking back.
Green, white.
He's dropped out of the field.
I was just going to say there's some men walking out there but you can totally understand at the pace of this game.
Almost unrelenting.
Past few minutes the ball's scaling.
The ball's going to be a bit more aggressive.
Almost unrelenting.
Past few minutes the ball's scarcely been off the pitch.
It's hardly been a peep out of Nick Berry's whistle but there's a light blast there for another Irish penalty.
And it's Jemison Gibson Park over the ball.
Winning the turnover penalty.
He has been everywhere.
Yeah the little man working hard.
Look at him.
He knows he's not going to get the ball.
He just wants the penalty for his club.
It just seems Rob that so much has happened in front of this Irish defensive wall.
The Scottish couldn't get him behind and when they did they didn't get the off-post they needed.
And it's played into the hands of the Irish team.
Quite enjoyed the secondary tackles as well from Ireland.
And they're not just content with that first up hit.
They're looking to try and secure the ball.
Stop that off-load and look the runners track them all the way through.
And it's been brilliant how they've done it.
Even at the point of absolute exhaustion they still look organised.
That Peña Baiona rings around Stade de France.
The adopted anthem of the French people.
Look at those stats.
Ireland making the vast majority of the tackles.
They've been asked to.
It's under five.
Okay, that's stop lines.
Final five minutes of the match.
Contest dominated by Ireland.
Tackle release.
Five minutes from the quarterfinals and from another blockbuster date with New Zealand and the All Blacks.
Ireland's attack has been excellent.
Ireland's defence too.
They conceded 13 tries in 11 matches in 2023.
It's up to 15 and 12 now.
It's been so impressive.
And for once the attack.
Thwarted by Scotland who set up the ball.
And it's been a great match.
Ireland's defence has been excellent.
Ireland's defence too.
They conceded 13 tries in 11 matches in 2023.
They've got them all.
Might have to put in at this scrimmage.
Not that many people have played Test Rugby.
Less have played it at a World Cup venue in a crucial must-win pool stage.
You can't really fault either side.
They've just put in so much work here.
But obviously the Irish have just showed that class.
Just showed that cohesion I think.
They seem to have more options in the opposition.
They've carved up the Scots early on.
It's a really, really tight outfit right now Rob Brickham.
The other teams we're looking in as to how to get in amongst this Irish team.
So many senior vets like that who are leading the charge.
Quality throughout the side.
And I think that's what's key to it all.
They are so comfortable in how they play Ireland.
You know their formations, you know their structures.
You can analyse them until you've got no time left in the week.
He's just trying to stop it.
Players in motion, their efficiency and interplay is what is setting them aside at the moment.
And their strength and depth is just ridiculous.
Yeah, that efficiency.
They don't seem to waste much energy out there.
And their lines have run.
It's such a well rehearsed team.
It's a credit.
It's a journey this Irish team has been on Jamie.
As you know you've been watching it from across the water there.
They've put in so much work for such a long time to get to this stage.
There were bleak days in the 80s and the 90s for Irish rugby.
When they lost to all manner of teams from all manner of countries.
They lost two out of two to Namibia.
They lost ten out of eleven to Scotland.
Eleven out of eleven to England.
They lost to Samoa, to Italy.
No longer.
So many people have contributed and know our colleague Hugo McNeil talks about the school system.
Particularly the register school system.
The likes of David Musa for us.
I work with Stephen Aboud who put a lot of time in that program.
So many have built this up.
School teachers, academy teachers.
And this is the result.
They're the best team in the world.
And for me, they've got to be the favourites going into these quarterfinals.
Crouch!
Fine!
Set!
Ireland penalty.
Elbow down, hinge.
You're lucid. Elbow down, hinge.
Just to explain, hinging is at the waist.
Holding that weight.
Probably some important minutes here for the substitute there.
The youngster Jack Crowley.
Hasn't all gone his way since he's been on there.
But you can't replicate this environment and the importance of it.
Looking at some of the stats on our monitor in front of us.
Some of the tackle numbers from Ireland.
21 apiece made by Josh Fundeflair and Cailan Dorris in the Irish back row.
Most of the pack well into double figures.
Bundy Aki too.
And now they have a chance to drive another dagger between Scottish ribs.
Here goes the splinter group.
Fundeflair and Kelliher in there.
Scotland dragging towards the touch line.
And the ball is available so Murray plays it away.
Ireland on the hunt for their seventh try of the night.
Murray, Dorris.
Tackle release!
Met hard and met early on the game line.
Murray plays once more to Fundeflair.
Massive power to weight ratio.
The explosive flanker.
And another Scottish penalty conceded.
Tackle is complete and he still played the ball there.
He's got to release the tackler.
Ireland managing the clock here.
You mentioned the back rowers, Fundeflair and Dorris.
You can't do what Ireland done here tonight.
Without those men doing the work.
The body of work. He's had 42 tackles between them.
Constant work and they're still going to pound away at the Scottish line.
Here we go.
Lorden Kelliher, a little false start.
Now he goes.
This has been a pummeling from the Irish pack.
And they are hungry for more.
Finlay Bealham hoovers up another Irish try.
The demolition job is complete.
There is a clear knock on by Green beforehand.
Clear knock on, no need to review.
Or not.
There was a knock on in the back beforehand.
We're going to have to play the strum.
Stop the music. Stop the commentator.
Finlay Bealham denied the try.
It's not going to matter in the grand scheme of things.
But there was a little fumble.
Of an Irish fingertip.
In the build up.
I'm not sure who it was.
So a couple of minutes left.
In fact the clock is about to tick into the red garrison.
Time to anoint your master card player of the match.
Yeah, outstanding work.
Started at scrum half for all the key moments.
Then moved out to the wing.
Jamison Gibson Park, your master card player of the match.
Saw his attacking stats there.
One of his most impressive interventions was.
Belt in Rory Sutherland.
Big beefy Scottish proper full tilt.
One v one on the wing.
Andy Farrell knows the job is done.
Claps.
And his features appearing on the big screen.
Has met with a ripple of approval.
From this huge Irish crowd.
Clock is red.
Last act for Scotland at the Rugby World Cup 2023.
They've got to go from 90 metres.
Just for a consolation try.
How much do they want it?
How much energy do they have left?
Sutherland again. Fandem Erba.
Still plenty of running left in those big legs.
The first time he makes metres it's coming to eighty first minute.
And then Scotland throw it away.
Ireland have it back.
And Ireland end the match.